Guide to the Cornell University examinations, 1869-1931.
Cornell University examinations,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University examinations, 1869-1931.
36-2-3877
Cornell University.
.6 cubic ft.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Printed entrance, scholarship, and class examinations, 1869-1931. Also "Lists of Candidates and Schedule of Examinations for Advanced Degrees," 1892-1913. Bound volume of entrance and class examinations, 1871-1879, with a list of reference books in the University Library, 1879, kept by the Chi Chapter of Psi Upsilon. Blank examinations for botany, undated; rhetoric, 1872; French, 1871, 1872; and German, 1873. Exams from Charles David Damsky, M.E. 1917 course E14 Elementary Electrical Engineering first prelim November 1, 1915, third prelim January 26, 1916, E15 Elementary Electrical Engineering Experiment B, E35 Electrical Engineering for Mechanical Engineering Seniors first prelim December 14, 1916. Second prelim February 8, 1917, History 54 Jacksonian democracy readings collateral to Fish Ch, X-XV, also additional study material. Also a sheet from the Office of the Registrar called Explination of Grading Systems. Also, "Examination Questions on the Lectures on Political Economy delivered by Prof. W. D. Wilson," 1871.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Printed entrance, scholarship, and class examinations, 1869-1931. Also "Lists of Candidates and Schedule of Examinations for Advanced Degrees," 1892-1913. Bound volume of entrance and class examinations, 1871-1879, with a list of reference books in the University Library, 1879, kept by the Chi Chapter of Psi Upsilon. Blank examinations for botany, undated; rhetoric, 1872; French, 1871, 1872; and German, 1873. Exams from Charles David Damsky, M.E. 1917 course E14 Elementary Electrical Engineering first prelim November 1, 1915, third prelim January 26, 1916, E15 Elementary Electrical Engineering Experiment B, E35 Electrical Engineering for Mechanical Engineering Seniors first prelim December 14, 1916. Second prelim February 8, 1917, History 54 Jacksonian democracy readings collateral to Fish Ch, X-XV, also additional study material. Also a sheet from the Office of the Registrar called Explination of Grading Systems.
Also, "Examination Questions on the Lectures on Political Economy delivered by Prof. W. D. Wilson," 1871.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Examinations.; Psi Upsilon Fraternity. Chi Chapter (Cornell University); Cornell University; Psi Upsilon Fraternity. Chi Chapter (Cornell University)
Subjects:
Universities and colleges -- Entrance examinations.; Examinations -- Questions.; Examinations; Universities and colleges -- Entrance examinations
Form and Genre Terms:
Examinations (documents); Questions
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also two bound volumes of examinations, Question papers used at the examinations for admission, call number LD1352.Q47.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Examination Questions - Assorted
Series II. Examination Schedules and Rules of Conduct
Series III. Entrance Examinations
Series IV. Other
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Examination Questions - Assorted
  - Questions and Topics for Examination in Logic, Prof. Ziba H. Potter - Spring Term, 1875 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter
  - Questions and Topics for Examination in Logic, Prof. Ziba H. Potter - Spring Term, 1874 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated
  - Outlines of Lectures on Psychology, Delivered Before the Junior Class in CU, By Professor W.D. Wilson - Fall Term (Arranged as Topics and Questions for Examination), 1881-1882 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Subjects and Questions for Examination in Psychology - Fall Term, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Subjects and Questions for Examination in Psychology - Fall Term, 1875-1876 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Examination Questions and Syllabus of the Lectures on Psychology, Delivered Before the Junior Class in CU, Prof. W.D. Wilson - Fall Term, 1874-1875 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Question Subjects for Examination on the Lectures on Psychology, Delivered Before the Junior Class in CU, Prof. W.D. Wilson - Fall Term, 1873-1874 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Examination Questions and Syllabus of the Lectures on Psychology, Delivered Before the Senior and Junior Classes in CU, Prof. W.D. Wilson - Fall Term, 1871-1872 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Lectures on the History and Criticism of Philosophy, and the Progress of Knowledge, Delivered Before the Senior Class of CU, Prof. W.D. Wilson - Fall Term + Subjects and Questions for Examinations, 1880 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Examination Questions on the Lectures on the Philosophy of History, Delivered Before the Senior Class in CU, Prof. W.D. Wilson - Winter Term, 1872-1873 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Questions and Subjects for Examination in the Philosophy of History, CU, Professor W.D. Wilson - Winter Term, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Subjects and Questions for Examination on the Lectures on Moral Philosophy, Delivered Before the Class in CU, Professor W.D. Wilson - Winter Term, 1875-1876 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Topics and subjects for Examination on the Lectures on American Law and Jurisprudence, delivered before the Senior Class in CU, Professor W.D. Wilson - Third Term, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; Text Books specially recommended: Story on the Constitution. Smith's Elements of the Laws.; annotated; "Phil Barnard" on the front
  - Examination Questions on the Lectures on Political Economy, Delivered Before the Senior and Junior Classes in CU, Prof. W.D. Wilson - Winter Term, 1872-1873 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Examination Questions on the Lectures on Political Economy, Professor W.D. Wilson - Winter Term, 1876-1877 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; "Phil Barnard" on the front; annotated
  - Examination Questions in Political Economy - CU - Winter Term, 1878-1879 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; written name on the front
  - Subjects and Questions for Examination in Political Economy - CU - Winter Term, 1880-1881 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - C: Cornell University - Physics, 1874-06-23 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; instructions on the front: "Do not fold your papers. Write your name on each page of answers. Give solutions of problems in full."
  - A: Electricity and Magnetism - Winter and Spring Terms, 1875 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - C: Optics - Summer Term, 1876 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; "Phil Barnard" on the front
  - Electricity and Magnetism, 1876-06 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated; 10 questions; question #1 begins with: "Describe the friction electric machine (plate machine), …"
  - Heat, 1877-12 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions and 3 problems; 2 copies; question 1: "What are the various effects of heat?"
  - Acoustics and Optics - Winter Term, 1877-03-19 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam
  - Electricity and Magnetism, 1877-06 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated; 12 questions
  - Mechanics - Fall, 1878 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 12 questions; question 1 begins: "Define velocity"
  - Acoustics and Optics - Winter Term, 1878 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; questions 1 -6 for Acoustics and questions 7 - 12 for Optics
  - Optics - Summer Term, 1878 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "Show how the index of refraction of a substance …"
  - Electricity and Magnetism - Examinations from 8 to 11, 1879-03 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 12 questions; "[Two questions may be omitted.]" on the front
  - Electricity and Magnetism, 1879-06-10 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; a note on the front: "N.B. -- Students who were conditioned last term will remove that condition if …"
  - Examination in Heat, 1879-12-16 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; note at the top: "Leave a blank line between answers and write the number of each question conspiciously whether you try to answer it or not."
  - Mechanics - Fall Term, 1880 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "How is force measured?"
  - Acoustics and Optics, 1880-03 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "What is a musical interval?"
  - Optics - Spring Term, 1880-06-08 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; note at the top: "Seniors under examination in this subject should notify the Professor in charge when they hand in their papers."
  - Electricity and Magnetism, 1881-03-22 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "Give the evidence that there are two kinds of electricity."
  - Heat, 1881-12-13 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1: "What are the principal effects of heat?"
  - Electricity and Magnetism - Spring Term, 1881 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questionsl annotated; 2 copies; question 1 begins: "What is the effect of a current flowing through a conductor?"
  - Acoustics and Optics, 1882-03-21 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "Name and describe the qualities of a musical note."
  - Syllabus of Lectures on Chemistry - Second Term, 1877 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated; 27 questions; question 1 begins: "Berthollet's laws."
  - Examination in General Chemistry, 1878-06-12 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; annotated; question 1: "Mention the important compounds of sodium which occur in nature."
  - Examination in General Chemistry, 1880-03-24 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1: "Give the definition of an acid."
  - Cornell University - Syllabus of Lectures on Chemistry, Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated; 25 questions for Theoretical Chemistry and 5 questions on Inorganic Chemistry; 2 copies
  - Inorganic Chemistry, 1880-12-13 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; question 1: "What is an acid?"
  - General Chemistry, 1881-06-08 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 6 questions; question 1: "Give the formulae of the compounds of sodium which occur more frequently in nature."
  - Astronomy, 1879-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 12 questions; 11 A.M. - 1:30 P.M.; question 1 begins: "Explain the two causes fo the differnce between mean and apparent time."
  - Physical Astronomy, 1881-06-07 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 6 questions; note at the top: "[Illustrate by drawings whenever the question permits.]"
  - Descriptive Astronomy - Professor Oliver, Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; Room 3 Sibley, 11 a.m.
  - Physiological Botany, Final Examination, 1876-06-05 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 15 questions; question 1 begins: "What method is best adapted to the study of Flower, …"
  - Botany - Second Preliminary Examination - Spring Term, 1879-05-23 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions
  - Botany - Final Examination - Spring Term, 1879-06-09 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 20 questions
  - Examination in Physiological Botany, 1881-06-06 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 15 questions; question 1: "What should be the chief characteristics of a typical flower?"
  - Examination Papers on the Lectures on Geology, Prof. Ch. Fred Hartt, M.A. - Spring Term, 1871-1872 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Examination in General Geology, 1878-12-19 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; exam divided into parts: Physiography, Lithology, Petrology, etc., Dynamical Geology, Historical Geology, Miscellaneous; annotated
  - Examination in Geology, 1879-12-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 7 questions; handwritten exam in purple ink
  - Exam on Army (1), Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; no original title; 6 questions; question 1: "Discuss the following topics: (a) Bases of operation, (b) Lines of operation, (c) The supply of armies in the theatre of war"
  - Exam on Army (2), Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; no original title; 6 questions; question 1: "Discuss the general considerations which precede the opening of a campaign"
  - Cornell University - Lectures on Physiology - Fall Trimester, 1874-1875 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; outline of lectures and a syllabus
  - Programme of General and Special Instruction in Physiology, Zoology, Comparative Anatomy and Economic Entomology, With Rules of Health, 1875-1876 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; name signed on the front; outline of lectures and syllabus for Human Physiology and Hygiene (fall trimester)
  - Synopsis of Lectures on Veterinary Science - First Term, 1879-1880 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Examination in Building Materials and Construction - Spring Term, 1879 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 15 questions
  - Examination on Renaissance, 1880-12-13 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10 questions; handwritten exam in purple ink; could not decipher full original title
  - Handwritten Exam in Purple Ink, Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; original title not found; question 10: "Name the various kinds of structures to which the Romans applied architecture."
  - Cornell University - Arithmetic A, 1875-09-13 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 questions; question 2 begins: "How many feet and inches deep is a rectangular pit … "
  - Cornell University - Arithmetic B, 1875-09-13 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated; 8 questions; question 2 begins: "A wall 5 feet high and 1 foot thick contains 5,400 bricks, "
  - Arithmetic, 1876-09-11 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 7 questions; question 1: "Write in figures, using the proper commas and decimal-points, One Hundred and Two Billion, Thirty Million, …"
  - Arithmetic, 1878-06-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Describe the Roman notation, …"
  - Arithmetic, 1878-09-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Define: --A Unit; …"
  - Arithmetic, 1879-09-16 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 questions; 2 copies and second copy is annotated; question 1 begins: "What number added to XCVII will amount to CCVI?"
  - Geometry, Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated; 6 questions; question 1: "A perpendicular is the shortest line that be drawn from a point to a line."
  - Plane Geometry, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "If the opposite sides of a quadrilateral be equal each to each, …"
  - Plane Geometry, 1878-06-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; drawings; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Define: --A Surface, a Plane, a Line, …"
  - Plane Geometry, 1878-09-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; annotated; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Define: --An Angle, a Right Angle, an Acute Angle, …"
  - Plane Geometry, 1879-09-16 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 6 questions; question 1 begins: "Define: a regular polygon, similar polygons, …"
  - Solid Geometry, 1877-09-20 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 4 questions; question 1: "The sum of any two face-angles of a triedral angle is greater than the third"
  - Geometry, 1878-03-26 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 questions; "Phil Barnard" on top of page; question 1: "Define -- a plane, …"
  - Solid Geometry, 1878-09-19 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 A.M.; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "Define:--A Prism, A Zone, A Spherical Triangle, …"
  - Solid Geometry and Conic Sections, 1879-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 9 questions; question 1: "Planes perpendicular to the same straight line are parallel to each other."
  - Solid Geometry and Conic Sections, 1880-03-23 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2:30 - 5:30 P.M.; 9 questions; question 1: "Define: The plane angle of a diedral angle, …"
  - Geometry and Conic Sections, 1880-12-14 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2:30 - 5:30 P.M.; 8 questions; question 1: "Define: a right angle, the inclination of a line to a plane, a prism."
  - Algebra. B. (First Sheet), 1875-09-13 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; calculations on the back; 5 questions; question 1 begins: "How do you perform algebraic subtraction; …"
  - Algebra. A. (First Sheet and Second Sheet), 1875-09-13 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; one drawing on the back; 9 questions in total; question 1 begins: "How do you transpose a quantity from one side of an equation to the other; …
  - Algebra through Quadratics [not for those examined in Algebra Entire] Second Paper, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 (1/4) p.m.; questions #5-9
  - Algebra through Quadratics [not for those examined in Algebra Entire] First Paper, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 11 a.m.; questions #1-4
  - Algebra ---Afternoon, 1877-06-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; part of an exam; questions #5-8; handwritten exam; question 5 begins: "Clear the following equation from radicals, and solve it"
  - Algebra Entire -- Second Paper, 1878-01-08 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2 (1/2) p.m.; questions #7-10; handwritten exam; question 7(a) begins: "Solve the equations"
  - Algebra Entire -- Second Paper, 1878-09-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; questions #6-8; note at the top of page: "Questions 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, as in 'Algebra Through Quadratics'"
  - Algebra, 1878-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 (1/2) p.m.; 9 questions; 2 pages
  - Algebra -- Through Quadratics, 1879-09-16 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 3 p.m.; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "Find the lowest common multiple of"
  - Algebra --, 1879-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 10:30 a.m.; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "Reduce 34/49 to a continued fraction"; could not decipher original title
  - Algebra Entire -- First Paper, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 11 a.m.; questions #1-5; 2 pages; question 1(a) begins: "What is meant by a 'negative quantity'?"
  - Algebra Entire -- Second Paper, 1877-09-18 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2 pages; 2 (1/4) p.m.; questions #6-12; question 6(a) begins: "Find x, y, and z from the equations"
  - Cornell University, Entrance Examinations - Higher Algebra, 1880-09-16 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 10:30 a.m. - 1:30 p.m.; 10 questions; annotated; question 8 begins: "State and prove the rule for finding the equal roots of an equation …"
  - Cornell University, Entrance Examinations - Elementary Algebra, 1881-09-14 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 - 6 p.m.; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "Define: Algebra, an unknown quantity, a polynomial, …"
  - Algebra, 1882-03-21 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 - 6 p.m.; 11 questions; question 1 begins: "Define: rational, irrational, radical, …"
  - Trigonometry, 1879-06-10 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Show that cos(a-b) …"
  - Trigonometry, 1880-06-08 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in purple ink; 2:30 p.m. - 5:30 p.m.; 9 or 10 questions; a piece of exam ripped off; could not decipher entire original title
  - Trigonometry, 1881-06-07 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 3 - 6 p.m.; 7 questions; 2 questions for THEORY OF EQUATIONS; question 1 begins: "Define the six principal trigonometric functions …"
  - Plane Analytic Geometry, 1876 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 9 o'clock a.m.; Sibley Building; 9 questions; questions in Roman numerals; possibly Dec. 13, 1876
  - Geometry of 3 Dimensions, 1878-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 10 a.m.; Sibley; 4 questions; could not fully decipher original title; question 1 begins: "Find equation of sphere whose centre is at …"
  - Plane Analytic Geometry, Technical Courses, 1877-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 8 a.m.; 6 questions; 2 pages; question 1(a) begins: "Draw carefully an ellipse, …"; could not completely decipher original title
  - Analytic Geometry, 1879-12-17 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in very light green ink; 2:30 p.m.; 8 questions; 2 pages; question 1 begins: "Find the coordinates …"
  - Analytic Geometry of 3 Dimensions, Undated (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 12 pages; 5 sections
  - Analytic Geometry of 3 Dimensions, 1880-03-26 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam in very light green ink; 8 a.m.; 6 questions; 2 pages
  - Analytical Geometry, 1880-03-26 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 8 - 11 a.m.; 10 questions; question 1 begins: "Refer a straight line to oblique axes …"
  - Analytical Geometry, 1880-12-15 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2:30 - 5:30 p.m.; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Find the expression for the angle between two straight lines in a plane."
  - Analytical Geometry, 1881-12-14 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; 2:30 - 5:30 p.m.; 8 questions; question 1 begins: "Find the cosine of the angle …"
  - Differential Calculus and Analytic Geometry of Three Dimensions, 1877-03-20 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 2:15 p.m.; 10 questions; 2 pages; question 1 begins: "Show that the limit of …"
  - Differential Calculus, 1878-03-25 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    Gift from The Chi of Psi Upsilon Chapter; handwritten exam; 7 questions; question 1 begins: "What is meant by the limit of any expression?"; initialed J.E.O